Turns out I've been estimating my dog's
age wrong because multiply by seven is
not a real thing. You know, dog years.
My dog at one is the same as a human at
seven and at two they're 14. That Not
backed by any real research, not a real
thing. Instead, geneticists created this
chart and it's curved, which blows my
mind. So here, a dog at one is
equivalent to a person at 30 instead of
seven. But at 14 they'd be 70, not 98.
Dogs and humans age at different rates.
Dogs age faster than we do when they're
young and slower when they're old. Or if
you really want to freak yourself out,
we as humans age slower than dogs when
we're young and faster when we're old.
But this chart only looked at one breed
and new data from 117 different breeds
shows that there [music] isn't just one
curve, there are multiple with larger
dogs aging faster and smaller dogs aging
slower. [music] And what they're
actually measuring is the same kind of
biological clock that researchers are
studying in us. So to see more,
>> [music]
>> subscribe.